number 84 the chemical structure of
inositol formerly known as the vitamin
B8 is shown below
draw a chair conformation of this
molecule
so let's
draw it this way
now let's call this
carbon one two three four five six so
this is going to be one
I'm going to put 2 here
and then 3 4
5.
so on carbon one we have the o h group
it's on the wedge
it's coming out of the page so
let's put the first group in the axial
up position
now on carbon two
this second oh is on the wedge as well
so it's going to be going up
so this has to be equatorial up
there's only two options equatorial up
or axial down
and these two have to be on the same
side either they're both up or both down
now in carbon 3 we have an oh going into
the page
so that's going to be going in the
downward Direction so it's not going to
be axial up but it has to be equatorial
down
now let's move on to carbon 4.
so this is out of the page
and that's going to be up the same as
that one
so either it's axial down or equatorial
up
we're going to go with equatorial up
now for carbon 5 it's down
it's going
into the page so it's either axial down
or equatorial down
this is going to be
equatorial down
now this one is up
so either we have axial down or
equatorial up
so this is going to be equatorial up
so notice that
five of the six hydroxyl groups are in
the equatorial position
so the chair conformation this
particular chair conformation is
relatively stable
now if we were to take this o h
and put it in this Direction all the
other positions will be flipped we would
have five hydroxyl groups in the axle
position
rather than what we see here so this
particular Shear conformation is more
stable than the other one that we can
draw
so that's the chair conformation for
inositol
vitamin B8 or what used to be vitamin B8